LUKE TOMLINSON

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with experience in mobile application and cloud development. I have experience in project leadership and technical mentorship. I love helping others grow. I am a quick learner who enjoys challenging problems and diving into new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WillowTree, LLC | Durham, NC

June 2016-Present

Senior Software Engineer | July 2019 - Present

- Served as technical lead and senior engineer for a large B2B iOS project using RxSwift
- · Mentored junior developers in iOS best practices
- · Built Continuous Integration pipeline from scratch using Azure Devops
- · Provided technical and architectural guidance to the client
- Redesigned and automated a client's application release process to simplify the number of deployments and reduce confusion
- Developed new features with newly developed APIs
- Helped develop APIs using Node, Typescript, and NestJS
- Deployed APIs to AWS using Docker and ECS Fargate
- Built a prototype iOS/tvOS application to become a certified TV partner with Apple
- Led multiple projects that generated new business for the organization

Platform Software Engineer | Nov 2017- Jul 2019

- · Led feature development for several iOS projects
- Built features such as data persistence, deep links, universal links, push notifications
- · Worked as a full stack engineer on a national magazine app
- Implemented API endpoints using AWS Lambda
- · Improved frontend by identifying and fixing performance issues
- Improved several CI pipelines using TeamCity
- Interviewed software engineering candidates for WillowTree
- Organized a regular company-wide iOS office hours to facilitate iOS knowledge sharing across the organization

Software Engineer | Jun 2016- Nov 2017

- Worked on iOS team to develop and maintain a national news app
- · Migrated parts of legacy codebase from Objective-C to Swift
- Collaborated with third party vendors to resolve dependency issues

marshall819@gmail.com

(513) 377-2992



Durham, NC

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Cedarville University

Summa Cum Laude

SKILLS

iOS Development

Backend Development

Continuous Integration/Devops

Leadership

Mentorship

Quick Learner

Self Motivated